Guide to the Severinghaus family papers, 1922-1994
Severinghaus family papers, 1922-1994
- Series I. Personal
  - Journal/diaries/memoirs/planners
    - Christmas greetings address list (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Christmas newsletters, 1967-76 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook - newspaper clippings, mostly German, c. 1871-80 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Das Sonntagsbuch (German songbook), 1914 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Travel journal - Holy Land? (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Prayer scrapbook (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Comparative Statistical Record of Charges for Michigan District, Central German Conference (Methodist Episcopal Church), 1917-26 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus Diary, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus Terre Haute school book - essays (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Gospel Hymns No. 5 (Charles E. Severinghaus), 1897 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus Diary, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus Diary, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus expense journal, 19113? (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - Small notebooks, diaries, bank books (Box 10, Folder 12-31)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - "The Pastor's Vade Mecum", 1916 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - "Daily Suggester", 1942 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - sermons, stories, other writings (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - mss. of life history, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - "Talks given - Talks not accepted"; PTA meeting address, 1953-54, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - notes on sermons? (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - insurance for Leslie and Aura (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - Ohio minister's license, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - Terre Haute High School graduation program, 1884 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Leslie Severinghaus's introduction to "Discovery " (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "A Brief autobiography by Charles Edwin Elmer Severinghaus - 1865-1962", c. 1982 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Volume I: Discovery - "Family Affair"... 1896-1907 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Volume II: Discovery - "Family Affair... March 1907-March 1913 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Volume III: Discovery - "Family Affair"... March 1913-August 1915 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Volume III: Discovery - "Family Affair" - items inserted into Leslie Severinghaus annotated copy (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Volumes IV-XIII: Discovery - "Family Affair" - 1915-1925 (Box 12, Folder 7-17)
    - Discovery addendum (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 1897-1904: Tengchow-Weihsien Move - - - Yale in Hunan (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Discovery - A Family Story: four Diaries by Emmavail Luce, 1916-1919 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Severinghaus trip to China, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Elisabeth Luce Moore - A Spoken History, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - "Going Home" - The Record of a Journey - 1927 - journal logs and correspondence, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Leslie Severinghaus (?) Diaries, 1965, 1969,1990-93 (Box 13)
    - Leslie Severinghaus (?) Diaries, 1971-72, 1977-78, 1982, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Leslie Severinghaus (?) Diaries, 1971-80 (Box 15)
  - Additional Personal
    - Address book (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Severinghaus genealogy (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Luce genealogy (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Address by Clare Booth Luce before the Annapolis Naval Academy: "History and the Nature of Man" (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Philippines: A Background, 1970-80 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Severinghaus Reading Room Dedication and Manuscripts and University Archives exhibit material, 1990, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Memorial Service, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Memorial, dedications, obituaries - Severinghaus and Luce, 1984, 1985, 1987 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Eastern Baptist Theological Seminary Layman's Award and newspaper clippings, 1955 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - "The Lady in the Painting" - Chinese Reading Booklet for corresponding instructional audio tapes (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Paintings of Wu Ch'ang Shou and Ch'i Pai Shih (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - An Illustrated Life of Confucius (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - sheet music - composed by L. K. Severinghaus (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - sheet music - composed by Lois S. Perkins, 1940 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - "The Daisy Chain - Twelve Songs of Childhood", 1900 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Holiday magazine - p. 89 photograph of Haverford School class of 1970, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - "Moon Cakes and Maple Sugar" by Marnie Copland, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Chinese Wit Wisdom and Written Characters by Rose Quong, 1944 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - The Use of Material from China's spiritual Inheritance in the Christian Education of Chinese Youth, 1932 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - China Scenes, 1980 (Box 59, Folder 8)
- Series II. China
  Includes correspondence, student work, teaching material, student directories, publications, and reference and support material related to Leslie Severinghaus's employment as an English professor at the Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) as well as his later association with the institution; material pertaining to Leslie Severinghaus's association with the American Commemorative Bureau; and material relating to Leslie Severinghaus's involvement in the American Oral English project (SLUR) under the auspices of the ABMAC at the National Defense Medical Center in Taipei.
  - Peking Union Medical College (PUMC)
    - Shanghai American School - Correspondence (Yenching faculty) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - PUMC - directory correspondence (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
    - PUMC - Directories and directory information (Box 16, Folder 4-6)
    - Check-list, names/addresses (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - The English Novel - 18th and 19th Century given to II year Medical Class - I and II trimesters - PUMC, 1925-26 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - PUMC - Student Work - Papers, 1926-27 (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    - PUMC - Student Work, 1922-27 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - PUMC - Student Work: "The Third Trimester", 1926-27 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - PUMC - Student Work - compositions submitted for "The Third Trimester" (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - PUMC - Student Work (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - PUMC - pamphlets, announcements, brochures (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - PUMC - Aura Severinghaus account with Asia Banking Corporation - statements, 1920-23 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - PUMC Dedication Book, 1921 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - PUMC - assorted material (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - "China Mementoes" (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - PUMC - additional material (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - American Bureau of Medical Aid for China (ABMAC)
    - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, Inc. (ABMAC) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - ABMAC and related (Box 17, Folder 3-6)
  - American Oral English Program (SLUR)
    - American Oral English - project proposal (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - SLUR - Franklin & Marshall Language Project (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - American Oral English Programs - reports, other material (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - SLUR Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Program Feedback (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "SLUR - Level One" (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - SLUR - Exercises (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - American Oral English (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Series III. Schools
  Includes correspondence, publications, and other material related to Leslie Severinghaus's employment as English teacher and headmaster at The Haverford School, as well as material from continued association with that institution; correspondence, records, and other material related to Leslie Severinghaus's service as a consultant and interim headmaster at The Palmer School' correspondence, records, publications, travel ephemera, and photographic material from the Severinghaus; service to the Green Mountains International Work and Language Camp at Goddard College ('The Experiment'); and correspondence, records and other material related to The Headmaster's Association, The Country Day School Headmaster's Association, and the Arden House Colloquium.
  - Haverford School
    - Personal Correspondence, 1965-68 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Publications/Pamphlets/Newsletters (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
    - Haverford School Quarterly (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Henry Luce Foundation Library (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Haverford School (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Photograph (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Form Standing" charts, 1939-62 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - II - VI Form - photographs (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Haverford School - 36-year survey chart (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Haverford School (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Parents' Nights (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Talks, illustrated talks, commencement speeches, etc., 1942-47 (Box 19, Folder 15-16)
    - Haverford School - "Religion in Human Experience" (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Leslie Severinghaus's re-evaluation of religion class at Haverford, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - "Senioritis" booklet - order form and cover (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Haverford School miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 20-24)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - "A Pictorial Outline of a Year at Haverford 1945-46", 1945-46 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Haverford (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Palmer
    - Palmer School (Box 20, Folder 1-8)
  - "Experiment": Green Mountains International Work and Language Camp at Goddard College
    - Correspondence (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
    - Travel records/arrangements (Box 21, Folder 5-7)
    - Travel journal (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Green Mountain International Work and Language Camp Correspondence (5), 1939-40 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Green Mountain International Work and Language Camp Correspondence, 1939-41 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Green Mountain International Work and Language Camp at Plainfield, Vermont, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Experiment" International Living, 1938-48 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Experiment", 1937 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "Experiment" - Scandinavia, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Experiment" literature (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
    - Emmavail Severinghaus - introduction to "Experiment" (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - "An Experiment in International Living" - damaged manuscript (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Headmasters' Associations
    - Headmaster's report to Board of Directors, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Headmaster's Association (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Country Day School - Headmaster's Association Directory, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Middle States Association - Commission on Secondary Schools, 1961-62 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Country Day School Headmasters' Association (Box 22, Folder 5-7)
    - Arden House Colloquium Leslie Severinghaus was chair), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Series IV. Cornell
  Includes correspondence, reports, and publications related to Severinghaus' alumni activities at Cornell University, including trustee papers, presidential searches, admissions policies, student uprisings, the East Asia Program, the Laboratory for Ornithology, gifts to the university, reunions, and the 1984 Adult University Cruise aboard the 'Sea Cloud'.
  - Cornell University - Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Cornell University - Gift Correspondence, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Interesting documents" from work with Cornell University (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Cornell University miscellany (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Trustee, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Trustee papers, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Trustee papers, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Trusteeship Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
  - Cornell University Presidential Councilor (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Student Uprisings/Protests (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Presidential Searches, etc. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "A Philosophy for College Admissions" (1) - letters, reprints, etc. - written first for Cornell, modified and published in the ACAC Journal, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Leslie Severinghaus speaking tour, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - East Asia Program, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - East Asia Program related material (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Material/correspondence for Cornell Alumni News article, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Reunion '21, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Cornell - Adult University - cruise aboard "Sea Cloud", 1984 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Guest book of Cornell Club of Miami, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - An Oral History Interview with Deane W. Malott, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Cornell University related publications (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - "Million Dollar Class Award", 1991 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Fund Reunion Campaign award, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Recording: James Perkins' Inauguration Address, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Songs of Cornell (Box 23, Folder 26)
- Series V. Travel
  Contains correspondence, journal entries, and ephemera related to the travels of Leslie Severinghaus, Emmavail Severinghaus, and Sheldon Root Severinghaus. Material is chronologically ordered, beginning with Emmavail Luce's 1921 journey to England.
  - Emmavail - England, 1921 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Emmavail Severinghaus and RLS - return trip from China, 1927 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Emmavail Severinghaus and Leslie Severinghaus - "Around the World", 1932 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
  - Taiwan, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - World Trip with Garside, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Emmavail Severinghaus and M. T. Moore - Trip Around the World, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Journals: Florida trips, 1955,-58-64 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Journals: New Orleans and Texas trip, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Emmavail Severinghaus and Leslie Severinghaus journal - trip to California, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - ERS and Leslie Severinghaus - trip to U.S. Rockies by Jeep, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Asia, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Leslie Severinghaus Taiwan trip, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 12-14)
  - Africa, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Asia, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Galapagos Islands, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Florida trip, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - India, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Seychelles Islands, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Africa, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Taiwan, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Hong Kong and around Taiwan, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - New Zealand, Australia, Bali, Taiwan, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Africa, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Everglades National Park, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - "Beth" to "Tex" Correspondence - China, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Leslie Severinghaus to Taiwan, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Far East, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Far East - Maps, pamphlets, etc., 1982 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - China, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - China - Maps, pamphlets, etc., 1983 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - English Readers, miscellany (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Travel (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Guidebook to Angkor with notes (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Maps, brochures, guide books (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Guide books (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - China trip memoria (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Far East with Boles, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Glee Club - Asia tour, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - China, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Retirement travel log, 1965-75 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Fragments (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Travel ephemera (postcards/snapshots) (Box 33, Folder 7)
- Series VI. Subject Files
  A. Religion, State, Schools: Contains correspondence, manuscripts, and support material related to the publication of Leslie Severinghaus' book, Religions and History, and his efforts to introduce the instruction of world religions to private schools.
  B. Wellesley: Contains correspondence, publications, speech outlines, year books, a scrap book, and ephemera pertaining to Emmavail Severinghaus' student and alumni involvement with Wellesley College.
  C. Speeches/addresses: Consists of speech outlines and compositions, as well as transcribed speeches given by Leslie Severinghaus to various organizations and institutions. Also contains a chronological collection of reactions to the speeches in the form of correspondence.
  D. Financial: Contains material related to trusts, donations, and personal finances.
  E. Directorships: Contains material related to various institutions and organizations of which LEslie Severinghaus was a director.
  F. Audubon: Contains material pertaining to Severinghaus' involvement with the Tropical Audubon Society.
  G. Newspaper Clippings: Contains unsorted newspaper and periodical clippings collected by Leslie Severinghaus, as well as a collection of clippings pertaining to China.
  H. Hartford Outline: An unknown outline, possibly a manuscript, about missions in China. Labeled 'Hartford Outline'.
  - Religion, State, Schools
    - "Religion in Human Experience" (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Religions and History - support material (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Religions and History - correspondence (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Religions and History - Personal response correspondence/promotion (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Religions and History - world religion map (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Religions and History - support material (Box 24, Folder 6-8)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus - "The Celebration of the Quadri-Centennial of Luther and the Reformation" (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Religions and History - draft copy (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Religions and History - related correspondence, Robert J. Dilzer, Jr., 1989 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Religions and History - Gift Book Responses from Independent Schools (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
    - Religions and History - book (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Education Proposal, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Common Sense and the Constitution, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Collected publications, periodicals, pamphlets, booklets (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Wellesley (Emmavail)
    - Emmavail (?) Wellesley scrapbook (Box 26)
    - Wellesley College (Correspondence) (Box 24, Folder 29-30)
    - Wellesley College (Publications) (Box 24, Folder 31-32)
    - Emmavail Severinghaus - Wellesley reunion sash and pin (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Wellesley "Legenda", 1920 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Wellesley "Legenda", 1921 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Speeches/addresses
    - Leslie Severinghaus - speeches/addresses (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - transcribed speeches/addresses (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1952-54 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1954-55 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1955-56 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1957-58 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1958-59 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1959-60 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1960-61 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1961-62 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1962-63 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Remarks on Speeches, 1963-64 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - 3x5 speech notecards (Box 27)
  - Financial
    - Financial - move from Haverford to Coconut Grove (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Financial - photographic inventory (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Financial - property tax (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Financial - Merrill Lynch Basic Value Fund, Inc. (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Financial - Volusia County Bonds (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Financial - Putnam Tax Exempt Income (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Financial - Merrill Lynch Pierce Fenner and Smith Inc. (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Financial - Time Inc. (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Personal Financial - original copies of H. R. Luce Trust Funds (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Directorships
    - East Ridge Retirement Village, Inc. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Eckerd College (chairman, Board of Visitors), 1969-74 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - The Dexter School (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - Vanguard School (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Audubon
    - Tropical Audubon Society (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Clippings (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
    - Asia newspaper clippings (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 28, Folder 12-13)
  - Hartford Outline
    - "Hartford Outline" I - VII (Box 28, Folder 1-7)
- Series VII. Visual Material and Ephemera
  Contains photographs of early and late Severinghaus and Luce families, travel, and The Experiment in International Living; 35mm slides of retirement travels; glass lantern slides and glass negatives taken by Charles E. Severinghaus of extended family, and many taken by Leslie at Cornell University and in Peking, China; 35 mm negatives of Severinghaus family life, annotated photograph albums of various subjects, including PUMC construction, the Luce family in Peking, travel, and commemorative and family events. Commemoration ephemera consists of plaques, medals, posters, paintings, drawings, degrees, and oversized photographs.
  - Photograph Albums
    - Photograph album - trip to Hong Kong, Taiwan, etc., 1973 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Photograph album - trip to Puerto Rico, Portugal, etc., 1971 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Photograph album - Luce Family, 1906-? (Box 35)
    - Photograph album - Aura E. Severinghaus visit to the Valley of the Lost Tribe and famous Trappist Monastery in North China, 1923 (Box 36)
    - Photograph album - Yenching University (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Photograph album - Emmavail? (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Photograph album - China ...1922 and China...1983, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Photograph album - Japan, Ithaca, etc., 1985 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Photograph album - collected by Leslie Severinghaus, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Loose items from back of album (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Photograph album - Christmas - China trip with Cornell University Glee Club, 1988-89 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Photograph album - Aura E. Severinghaus and Sara Nay wedding (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Photograph album - Vol. I-IV - Luce/Severinghaus Story (Box 39, Folder 3-6)
    - Photograph album - India (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Vail" (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Photograph album - early family; Leslie Severinghaus at Cornell University (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Photograph albums - China (Box 39, Folder 10-11)
    - Photograph album - early Leslie Severinghaus and Emmavail Severinghaus (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Photograph album - observance of Leslie Severinghaus' 90th birthday, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Photograph album - miscellany (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Photograph album - Vol. I (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Photographs
    - Photos (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Photos at Angkor (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Siam - numbered postcards (photos) annotated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Angkor - numbered post cards (annotated) (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Bangkok - annotated post cards (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
    - Bangkok - annotated photos (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
    - Photographs (Box 49)
    - Photographic - photographs, annotated post cards, negatives (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Photographic (negatives) (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Photo scrapbook (Box 50, Folder 4-5)
    - Green Mountain International Work and Language Camp - photographs (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Photographs (Box 51)
  - Slides
    - 35mm slides (Box 40-45)
    - Glass slides (Box 53-56)
    - Europe LRS, ELS and Sheldon part 1, 1956 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      Slides
    - Europe LRS, ELS and Sheldon part 2, 1956 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Western trip LRS, ELS part 1, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Western trip LRS, ELS part 2, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Western trip LRS, ELS part 3, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Bear trapping, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Newfoundland, 1959 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Western camp trip part 1, 1960 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Western camp trip part 2 Sheldeon and Dad (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Europe part 1 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Europe part 2, 1961 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Europe A reel 1, France, Spain, Gibraltar, Switzerland, London, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Europe A reel 2, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 6)